<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>RM Ludwig</title>
    <link>https://rxqx.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on RM Ludwig</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://rxqx.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://rxqx.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rxqx.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>RITA M. LUDWIG rludwig[at]uoregon[dot]edu rludwig.github.io  Education 2014-present Ph.D., Psychology, University of Oregon
2014-2015 M.S., Psychology, University of Oregon
2011-2012 M.A., Quantitative Methods in the Social Sciences, Columbia University
2005-2009 B.A., Psychology and Sociology, New York University
Publications Dunha, J., Barker, P., Baumert, A., Bentvelzen, M., Berkman, E.T., Buchholz, N., Buczny, J., Chen, Z., De Cristofaro, V., de Vries, L., Dewitte, S., Glacomantonio, M., Gong, R., Homan, M., Imhoff, R., Ismail, I.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neural Models of Self-control</title>
      <link>https://rxqx.github.io/research/neural-models-of-self-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rxqx.github.io/research/neural-models-of-self-control/</guid>
      <description>Self-control describes the psychological process of inhibiting one’s desire for an immediately available reward in favor of another, longer-term one. It is considered to be core component in successfully encouraging health-promoting behaviors, such as exercising, and avoiding behaviors detrimental to long-term health, such as consuming large amounts of junk food. It is therefore a popular topic of study for those interested in developing interventions to encourage lifelong health and well-being.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neurohackademy - The Tools We Used - Pt. 1</title>
      <link>https://rxqx.github.io/post/neurohackademy-recap/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rxqx.github.io/post/neurohackademy-recap/</guid>
      <description>This year I was lucky enough to be one of the attendees of Neurohackademy, a two-week workshop focused on reproducible and shareable neuroscience. The first week of this workshop featured a dazzling array of speakers from a variety of research backgrounds, including psychology, computer science, and biomedical engineering, who led demonstrations on data science tools and methods. The second week was spent putting these tools to use in groups, hacking on different projects that were then shared with everyone on the last day of the workshop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Planfulness Scale</title>
      <link>https://rxqx.github.io/research/planfulness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rxqx.github.io/research/planfulness/</guid>
      <description>The Planfulness Scale (Ludwig, Srivastava, &amp;amp; Berkman, 2018) is a 30-item measure that assesses the tendency for people to exhibit patterns of thoughts about goals that have been shown to encourage goal achievement in laboratory research. It weaves together previous work from achievement and personality psychology to provide an easily distributed metric of whether people tend to use evidence-backed goal-encouraging habits.
The original aim of developing this scale was to inform intervention research.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>