<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on RM Ludwig</title>
    <link>https://rxqx.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on RM Ludwig</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://rxqx.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Why grad students benefit from open science practices</title>
      <link>https://rxqx.github.io/post/why-grad-students-benefit-from-open-science-practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rxqx.github.io/post/why-grad-students-benefit-from-open-science-practices/</guid>
      <description>Open science badges created and maintained by the Open Science Collaboration
The Context We are in the midst of a paradigm shift in psychology. It has been less than ten years since the Simmons, Nelson, and Simonsohn &amp;ldquo;False-Positive Psychology&amp;rdquo; paper demonstrated &amp;ldquo;how unacceptably easy it is to accumulate (and report) statistically significant evidence for a false hypothesis,&amp;rdquo; calling into question the legitimacy of standard research procedures used in many psychology labs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neurohackademy - Intro to the Languages We Used</title>
      <link>https://rxqx.github.io/post/neurohackademy-recap/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rxqx.github.io/post/neurohackademy-recap/</guid>
      <description>This year I was lucky enough to be one of the attendees of Neurohackademy, a two-week workshop focused on reproducible and shareable neuroscience. The first week of this workshop featured a dazzling array of speakers from a variety of research backgrounds, including psychology, computer science, and biomedical engineering, who led demonstrations on data science tools and methods. The second week was spent putting these tools to use in groups, hacking on different projects that were then shared with everyone on the last day of the workshop.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>